Guide to the Severo Perez Papers
The Wittliff Collections
Severo Perez Papers
1972-2010
The Wittliff Collections https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu
Perez, Severo
SWWC.115
22 Linear Feet
44 boxes
The papers of filmmaker and writer Severo Perez span 1972-2010 and document his career in film and television, and as a writer. The bulk of the collection relates to his film work, especially his 1995 film, …and the earth did not swallow him.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Severo Perez, 2014.
Biographical Notes
Born in San Antonio, Texas in 1941, acclaimed filmmaker Severo Perez earned his B.A. in American Literature and Contemporary History from the University of Texas. Perez moved to Los Angeles in 1972 to pursue a career in the motion picture industry. His productions have won more than 50 awards, including three CINE Golden Eagles. Perez is also an accomplished playwright and novelist.
Perez began working in theater in 1974, teaming up with legendary actress Carmen Zapata to translate and adapt the Mexican play Los desarraigados (Uprooted) for American audiences. Later, Perez became playwright-in-residence at El Teatro Campesino, where he wrote Soldierboy with his wife, Judith Perez. That play is based on Perez's own personal story in San Antonio as the son of a returning U.S. soldier after World War II. Soldierboy has been staged around the country and appears in the 1989 anthology Necessary Theater: Six Plays About the Chicano Experience. Perez's credits as a dramatist also include Speaking of Cats, inspired by Tejana activist Emma Tenayuca and the 1938 pecan shellers strike in San Antonio.
Perez's 1995 film, …and the earth did not swallow him, is adapted from Tomás Rivera's classic 1971 Chicano novel, …y no se lo tragó la tierra, and follows the lives of a South Texas family of migrant farmworkers in the 1950s. Perez's nuanced, powerful film beautifully evokes the substance and spirit of Rivera's work, and it has won international critical acclaim, including top honors at film festivals worldwide. Some of these honors include the Gold Medal at the 12th Annual Television Movie Awards in 1997, Jury Award at Vina del Mar (Chile) International Film Festival in 1996, Sol Award CineSol at the 1995 Latino Film Festival, Best Feature at the San Diego Independent Film Festival in 1994 and the Minneapolis Rivertown Film Festival in 1995, Best of the Fest Audience Award at the Santa Barbara Film Festival in 1994, and Jury Award for Best Director at the Cairo International Film Festival in 1994.
In 1998, Perez finished a documentary, Willa Brown: An American Aviator, about a remarkable woman—a pioneering African American pilot who took to the air in the 1930s and defied Jim Crow laws. Her efforts led to Congress forming the renowned Tuskegee Airmen squadron. The film is currently distributed by Filmakers Library.
Perez's other films include a documentary on artist Carmen Lomas Garza: Carmen Lomas Garza: Looking Back; a family drama about a high school girl's desire to attend college, Dreams of Flying; a documentary about dancer-choreographer Rudy Perez, Countdown: Reflections on a Life in Dance, an adaptation of Mark Twain's The Notorious Jumping Frog of Calaveras County; a feature film on Tejano hero Juan Seguin; a documentary about immigrants in Southern California, There Goes the Neighborhood; an animated film about the history of writing, Astronauts and Jelly Beans; a drama about AIDS for young teens, Between Friends, a documentary about four retired African American men, Elders; as well as short documentaries on a wide range of subjects, including La Raza Unida's 1960s political uprising in Crystal City, Texas. He also negotiated the deal at Universal Studios that allowed Luiz Valdez to direct the film version of Zoot Suit.
In 2012 Perez published his first novel, The Challengers Aero Club, inspired by his documentary on aviator Willa Brown and other pioneering African American pilots in the early 20th century. The book was praised by Kirkus as "an engaging, thorough novel about forgotten heroes of aviation history."
Scope and Contents
The papers of filmmaker and writer Severo Perez span 1972-2010 and document his career in film and television, and as a writer. The collection is arranged into six series: 1) Film; 2) Television; 3) Plays; 4) Books; 5) The National Endowment for the Humanities; and 6) Audio and Video Materials.
Conditions Governing Access
Perez also donated an extensive amount of audiovisual material which includes film reels and prints for …and the earth did not swallow him as well as many of his other film projects. A complete list of these items can be provided upon request.
Index Terms
Subjects
Authors, American -- Texas -- 20th century; Screenwriters -- United States; Dramatists -- Texas; Motion pictures -- Production and direction
Subjects (Persons)
Perez, Severo
- Film, 1987-1997
  - …And the Earth Did Not Swallow Him…, 1995
    - Screenplay, 1989-1991
      - Draft, August 1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Draft (partial), August 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Draft, August 1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Draft - 2nd Draft, December 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4-11)
      - Draft - 2nd Draft, January 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft - 2nd Draft, February 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
      - Draft - 2nd Draft, March 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6-10, Box 3, Folder 1-3)
      - Draft, February 1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Draft, March 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5-7)
      - Draft plus one page from article in Hispanic Link Weekly Report, May 15, 1989, March 1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Draft, plus outline, April 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Draft, April 1991 (Box 3, Folder 10, Box 4, Folder 1-3)
      - Draft, rewrite, July 1, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Draft, American Playhouse rewrite, July, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Drafts, September 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Drafts, American Playhouse rewrite, September 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Drafts, undated (Box 4, Folder 8-9, Box 5, Folder 1-5)
      - Drafts, partial, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Draft, edits by Judy Perez, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Comments on screenplay by Julian Olivares, September 11, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Notes by Antonio Castañeda, September 15, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Comments and notes on screenplay drafts, by various NEH advisory council members: Ricardo Romo, Marta E. Sánchez, Rolando Hinojosa, Julián Olivares, Nicolás Kanellos, Alicia M. González, William Goetzmann, Arturo Madrid, September 1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Notes for rewrite, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Scripts, 1990-1991
      - Working version before production, July 18, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Working version before production, August 1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Working version before production (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
      - Working version before production, plus Adair and Armstrong script (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Script and supervisor's notes (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Shooting script, December 1990 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Shooting script, American Playhouse rewrite, December 1990 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - "Shooting script Tierra Productions" with Perez's notes, December 1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - "Lined script-Orig." with original script supervisor's notes (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Narrator's Script (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Draft of final script (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Production - Research, 1989-1991
      - Iowa Film Office Information Book (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Iowa Maps – Local Information (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Texas Maps – Local Information (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Samples of period clothing and shooting location (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Black and white photos by Russell Lee (copy prints) (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - National Geographic and Texas Journal, 1989, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Production - Art, undated
      - Storyboards – 8 1/2 x 11 Master (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Storyboards (Box 8, Folder 8-9)
      - Stage plan blueprints (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Outline and drawing instructions (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Sketch by César Martínez (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Production - Casting, undated
      - Casting photos and bios (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Resume for Antonio Ogaz (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Ernesto Salcedo, musician/composer resume and demo audiocassette (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Marcos Loya photo and bio (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Production Materials, 1990-1994
      - Call sheets (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Shooting schedule (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Shooting locations – South Texas (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Tierra production schedule (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Production schedule, July 6, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Tierra Locations/Breakdown (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Production Binder (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
      - Production Binder – Location Scouting, Casting List, Letters, Calendar, and Script (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Production Binder – Oneline Schedules, Press Releases, Letters, Photos (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - "Code Book" for every scene and reel (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Handwritten notes, one page (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Tierra Scholars Meeting (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Transcript of the Tierra Advisory Meeting, February 24, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Tierra Productions script with notes by Perez while shooting (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Tierra newsletter and other material (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Narrator's script, oneline schedule, and crew list (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Narrator's script, end credits (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Prairie House Motel Brochure (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Spanish subtitles draft, July 29, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Spanish subtitles draft, August 15, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Perez's outline for making …and the Earth did not swallow him…, August 15, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Various production materials, correspondence, notes (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Scene list (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Domestic Distribution - Television (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Production - Location Scouting Photographs, undated
      - Crystal City by Severo Perez (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Crystal City (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
      - Minnesota and Iowa – photos by Severo Perez (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - SC 27 Sunrise Hwy in Midwest (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Location Scouting Photos (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
      - "Cologne Catholic School, Rectory, & Cemetery" (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Cologne, Methodist Cemetery (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - "Tomas Rivera's Actual House" (Photo with Tomas Rivera's brother, Henry) (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - "Tomas Rivera's Zoo Island" (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Duncan, Iowa Field, Zoo Island (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Don Cleto Int. (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Don Cleto Ext. (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Cemetery – Duncan, Iowa (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Iowa Cemetery (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Crystal City Cemetery (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - "Ford Truck found near Sacramento" (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Location Photos (Box 13, Folder 12-18)
      - Miscellaneous Store Fronts, Rectories, etc. Drive-bys (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - San Antonio Locations (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - SC 15 + Salon Hidalgo (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - SC 16 + Cotton Field (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - SC 87 + Trailer/Carpenter Train (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - SC 128 Power Plant (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Potato + Carrot Farm, Midwest Farms, Clearance Iowa (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Midwest School (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - Haxton House California (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Chicken Coops – Garner, Iowa (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - Iowa Farm, Garner (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - Sugar Beet Field – Renfield Co. Minnesota (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - Minnesota Roadside Attractions, Barns, etc. (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Jordan, Minnesota (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - Small Schools, Minnesota (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - Crystal City Locals, Creeks & Rivers (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - Iowa – Potato – Muddy Field (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Production - Continuity Photos, undated
      - Day 1 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Day 2 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Day 3 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Day 4 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Day 5 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Day 6 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Day 7 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Day 8 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Day 9 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Day 10 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Day 11 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Day 12 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Day 13 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Day 15 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Day 16 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Day, September 2, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Day 20 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Day 21 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Day 22 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Day 23 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Day 24 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Day 25 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Day 27 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Assorted Days (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Piru Party Dance (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Set Shots (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Production - Photographs from the Film, undated
      - Photographs from the film, photos and negatives (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Photos of actor Marco Rodriguez (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Various photos and negatives (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Photographs during filming (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Color negatives, photos by Carlos Rene Perez (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Production stills photography (Box 19, Folder 3-4)
      - Photographs, Perez and others (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Photographs – Black and white 8 x 10 prints (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Photograph of Crystal City and Carrizo Springs; pen drawing of three men (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Production - Financial Materials, undated
      - Budget sheets (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - "Old Tierra Budgets" (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Tierra revised production budget (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Tierra reimbursement receipts (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Production manager budget (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Travel/Meals/Per Diem (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Art Department budget (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Production Binder used by Perez to track budget while shooting (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Budgets (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Receipts and invoices (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Production - Legal Materials, undated
      - Legal documents/contracts (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Film rental contract (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Screen Actors Guild documents (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - Screen Actors Guild information (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - "Agreement with Concha Rivera" (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - San Diego State University agreements (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - Moscow International Film Festival documents/agreement (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Production - National Endowment for the Humanities, undated
      - "Tierra Proposal – NEH" (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - "Tierra Reviews NEH Proposal" (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - "Working Draft – NEH Proposal" (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - NEH Grant documents and application (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - NEH application, budgets, panelist evaluation sheets (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - NEH Panelist evaluation sheets with comments (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Toby Quitscand and NEH Award Letter (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - NEH documents and correspondence (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Post Production, 1993
      - Editing notes (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Rough cut notes and scoring log (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Optical sheets/sound notes (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Foley tracks, sound effects (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Notes for music mix (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - "Tierra Credits" (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Tierra credits, September 28, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Trims from the editing of …and the Earth did not swallow him… (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - "Censorship of "'Earth'" (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Publicity - Press Releases, undated
      - Press Book and reviews-master (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Folder with cast photo, newspaper, and press release (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Press release/reviews (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Publicity - Reviews, 1994-1996, undated
      - undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - 1994-1995 (Box 23, Folder 5-6)
      - 1995 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - 1995-1996 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Publicity - Press, 1990, 1994-1996
      - Press (Box 24, Folder 1-4)
      - Newspapers, October 1990 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Newspapers, 1994-1995 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Photocopies of articles/newspapers, 1994-1995 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Photocopies of articles/advertisements, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Latin Style Magazine, includes a profile of Severo Perez (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Order forms for "…and the Earth did not devour him…" (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Promotional flyers, folders, and postcards (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - The 1993 Independent Feature Film Market Company Directory (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Montclair State Fotoescultura Exhibit (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Western Social Science Association 37th Annual Conference Abstract Book (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Publicity - Film Festivals, 1978, 1992-1997
      - 1978 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - 1992 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - 1993 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - February-September 1994 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - September 1994 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - 16th Independent Feature Film Market, September 1994 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - November-December 1994 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - February-March 1995 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - April-May 1995 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - June-October 1995 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Moscow International Film Festival, July 1995 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - International Cairo, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - 1996 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - 1997 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Other festival materials (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Elders, 1993
    - Screenplay draft, July 1993 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Screenplay draft, undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 28, Folder 6-11, Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Insurance Policy, Photoduplication forms, and SERVE Packet, undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Yolanda de Nuevo, undated
    - First draft and Franciscan communications (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Baptism file (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Publicity - invitation and poster (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Willa Brown: An American Aviator, 1996-1997
    - Screenplay, 1996-1997
      - Working Draft, May 1996 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Draft and handwritten notes, October 16, 1996 (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - Draft, January 7, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - Draft plus handwritten notes (Box 29, Folder 10)
      - Draft, undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
      - Script and post script (Box 29, Folder 12)
      - Copy edited script (Box 29, Folder 13)
      - Draft and notes [Removed from binder] (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Dan's Draft (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Partial Draft (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Production
      - Handwritten notes (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Notes, contact list, and phone logs (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Code Book notebook (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - "Film Search" (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Production Sound Sheets (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Publicity
      - "Willa Brown: An American Aviator" publicity card (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Printout of photographs – cast and crew from …and the earth…, Soldierboy production, and Yolanda de Nuevo (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Plaza de la Raza (Perez directed a film series there), 1987
    - "Chicano and Film" (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Plaza de la Raza clippings (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Plaza de la Raza articles, April 18, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Documentation of Screening Activities for Plaza de la Raza (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - "First Weekend – Press Kit" (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Carmen + Cesar (films on artists Carmen Lomas Garza & César Martínez), 1987
    - "Carmen + Cesar Proof Sheets and negs" (Box 31, Folder 1-3)
    - Director's Clapperboard for The Eraser (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Two white proof sheet containers labeled "Carmen + Cesar" (Box 32)
- Television, 1987-2001
  - Resume of Severo Perez and publicity originals (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - "Tune in Yesterday" (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - "Dreams of Flying" – Script, revised 3rd draft, January 1989 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Articles by Jesus Trevino and Melendez – Pelayo (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - "The Piñata Makers" – Photographs (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - "Seguin" – Executive summary, publicity, press releases (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Promotional brochures (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - "There Goes The Neighborhood" - Promotional cards (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - "Stand and Deliver" script [Working title "Walking on Water"] (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Manuel Ramos' "The Last Client of Luis Montez" – screenplay, April 11, 2001 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - "Alamo…The Price of Freedom" – shooting script, plus media, August 23, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - "Alamo – The Price of Freedom" (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Reviews for "Alamo – The Price of Freedom" (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - "El Norte/The North" – info and publicity (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - "Mother of the Sun/Madre del Sol" – Screening invitation (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Letter and clipping from Arthur Ramirez, March 14, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Note from DDLP and Kiki (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Learning Garden – Brochure, drawing of a cow, and photographs (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - "The Lost Year" (fragment of a script for an uncompleted stage play based in part on Tomás Rivera's …y no se lo tragó la tierra.) (Box 33, Folder 19)
- Plays, 1980-1997, undated
  - Soldierboy, 1980-1987
    - Scripts, 1980-1987
      - [Working Title: Brother's Keeper], 1980 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - [Working Title: Return of the Soldier], 1980 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - [Working Title: Return of the Soldier] First Draft, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Working Title: Return of the Soldier], 1980 (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Production script San Juan Bautista, September-December 1982 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Al Franklin, Stage Manager script, December 1982 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - January 1983 (Box 34, Folder 7-8)
      - January 1984 (Box 34, Folder 9, Box 35, Folder 1-3)
      - Draft with notes, January 1984 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - April 1985 (Box 35, Folder 5-9, Box 36, Folder 1)
      - "Working 11-86", November 1986 (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - "Not revised version", October 1987 (Box 36, Folder 3-5)
      - Work copy, undated (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - Draft, undated (Box 36, Folder 7-9, Box 37, Folder 1-3)
      - Draft with notes, undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - "Return of the Soldier" draft with notes (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Spiral notebook with handwritten draft plus partial typed draft (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Handwritten and typed draft (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Draft plus notes, casting photographs and bios (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Second draft and rewrite roughs, April 17, 1981 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Box for second draft and rewrite roughs, April 17, 1981 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Draft typed and handwritten (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Script draft handwritten and typed (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Draft with notes and pictures (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Script partial draft with notes, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Script partial draft, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Script partial draft, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Script partial draft with notes, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Script partial draft, January 1983 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous notes, research, maps, and pictures, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Soldierboy Stat – typed in various fonts, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Budget, July 30, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Publicity
      - Soldierboy cover photo (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - Newspapers (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - Magazines (Box 39, Folder 11)